## Will Knight

Carterton, West Oxfordshire



will.k.01@live.co.uk



07807 904232



linkedin.com/in/willk01

## Summary

I'm a Junior Web Developer with 3 years in the Tech industry and over a year of professionally building websites. I primarily work with WordPress, building websites with modern HTML, CSS, and JS/jQuery. I also have some experience with Git workflows, React and Python.

My current personal projects are my own website built with Gatsby (React), a Discord chat-bot in Python which takes a UK vehicle registration, and returns basic details about the vehicle from the DVLA VES API, and my home server or "homelab", built with server-grade hardware and primarily functioning as our household's 8TB NAS.

## **Experience**



#### 🔤 Junior Web Developer

Blue Smarty

Sep 2019 - Present (1 year 6+ months)

Working with WordPress, I built websites from scratch that met and exceed our client's specifications and expectations with cohesive and engaging designs. Often communicating directly to clients, I also implemented tweaks and changes, carried out website maintenance and identified and fixed issues on both client and internal websites.

During my time at Blue Smarty I have designed and built websites internally and for clients using HTML5, CSS3, PHP and JavaScript/jQuery, including our own website! I researched and utilised modern CSS frameworks for select website builds, brought in a more comprehensive IDE and development tools, and built up a personal knowledge/code base with handy references, information and snippets of code which helped to solidify what I have learnt at Blue Smarty.

Some examples of my work:

- blue-smarty.com Our own business website.
- crowninnenstone.co.uk Modern gastropub website
- thecotswoldlist.uk Internal project a business directory targeted at companies local to the Cotswold's.
- brilliantspace.com Brochure website for furniture company.
- brightonworks.space Brochure website for industrial units.
- lucypratt.com Artist portfolio site

### **Junior SEO and Web Developer**



Search Intelligence Ltd

Mar 2018 - Sep 2019 (1 year 7 months)

Day to day responsibilities include utilising various SEO strategies to build useful and relevant links to ours and our client's websites. In addition to SEO, I contributed to the development of multiple internal and client websites allowing me to develop my knowledge and skills with front-end development of WordPress using page builder plugins, HTML and CSS.



#### Technical Assistant

#### Cloudworxs

Oct 2016 - Nov 2017 (1 year 2 months)

My tasks and responsibilities included populating the various online stores including Amazon and eBay alongside computer hardware projects including refurbishment and repairs. I also assisted with pick and pack order fulfilment for products stored on-site.

#### **Education**



#### Abingdon and Witney College

Level 3 Extended National Diploma, Computer Science

2017 - 2019

Throughout the course I have obtained a wide variety of soft skills such as time and project management, and improved my communication and teamwork skills while significantly broadening my knowledge of the computing industry.

A selection of units include:

- Website Development
- Computer Networking
- Planning and Management of Computing Projects
- Software Design and Development Project
- Principles of Computer Science



#### Carterton Community College

2012 - 2017

During my time at Carterton Community College I took advantage of extracurricular opportunities such as a STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics) specialist school course which included a trip to the Big Bang Fair in 2014, in addition to a week-long residential trip in South Wales and a Junior Medic First Aid skills course.

#### Skills

CSS • HTML • WordPress • Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) • Web Development • Bootstrap 4/5 Front-end Development • Virtualisation • Computer Hardware • Ecommerce

#### **Honours & Awards**

# **Highly Commended Certificate - Group Working -** Carterton Community College Jul 2014

- Exceptional commitment to group working
- Willingness to help others improve their work and skills
- Exceptional effort in developing work for performance



## Winning team - Technology Tournament 2016 - Ashley Farmer, 2015-2016

President of the Rotary Club of Witney

Jun 2016

Myself and 3 others studying Level 2 BTEC Engineering were selected to compete as a team against 3 other schools in an engineering and technology tournament hosted at Cokethorpe School, Oxfordshire.

We were given the assignment to design and build a bridge from a limited selection of materials, that would carry a kilogram weight across its length without collapsing. The team with the best use of teamwork skills, organisation, and detailed design documentation, and constructed bridge best meeting these requirements in the four hours of concentrated application would win.